This slide compares three terms that are
sometimes used loosely module package and library
A module is the smallest of the
three concepts in this comparison It is
usually one Python file that contains reusable
code Examples include the built-in math module
or a file that we create ourselves
such as calculations dot P Y A
package is a folder that groups related
modules For example a package named analytics
could contain finance dot P Y health
dot P Y and reporting dot P
Y A library is a larger collection
of reusable tools Libraries may contain several
packages and many modules NumPy and Pandas
are good examples of widely used libraries
in data analytics A simple way to
remember the relationship is this Module means
file Package means folder Library means a
larger reusable collection of tools The exact
technical details can become more complicated in
professional software development but this simple
model
is enough for our course Use a
module when one file can hold a
related set of functions or constants Use
a package when the project contains several
related modules that should be grouped together
Use a library when a larger collection
of reusable tools is shared across many
tasks or projects As we move into
NumPy and Pandas later in the course
you will see that importing a library
gives us access to many organized tools
that other developers have already created and
tested